onlinetyari.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy

## **Privacy Policy**

We respect your privacy and value the trust you have placed in Next Door Learning Solutions Private Limited (“OnlineTyari”, “Company”, “Our”, “Us” and “We”). We are fully committed to securing our Customer information and privacy by complying with this Privacy Policy. 

This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which We collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from you (each, a "User") when you access or use our website www.onlinetyari.com ("Website"), mobile applications (“App”) and other online services (hereafter collectively referred as “Services”). 

This privacy policy applies to information collected from you through OnlineTyari Platform, email, text, and other electronic communication channels in connection with our Services. 

By using Our Services, you agree to be bound by terms of this Privacy policy. If you do not agree with our privacy policy and practices, you can choose to not use Our Services. 

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that Onlinetyari collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example), first name, last name, phone number, email address, date of birth, employment details, income details, gender information, Contacts permission, Precise location permission (non-continuous), Phone permission, SMS permission, Storage permission, geographic position, language, various types of Data and picture. 

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using OnlineTyari Platform.  
All Data requested by OnlineTyari Platform is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for OnlineTyari Platform to provide its services. In cases where OnlineTyari Platform specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without any consequences on the availability or the functioning of the service.  
Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Owner.  
Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by OnlineTyari Platform or by the owners of third-party services used by OnlineTyari Platform serves the purpose of providing the service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy, if available.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through OnlineTyari Platform and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Access to third-party accounts, Advertising, Analytics, Contacting the User, Content commenting, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Device permissions for Personal Data access, Displaying content from external platforms, Handling payments, Heat mapping and session recording, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Infrastructure monitoring, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Interaction with live chat platforms, Interaction with support and feedback platforms, Location-based interactions, Managing contacts and sending messages, Managing support and contact requests, Platform services and hosting, Registration and authentication, Remarketing and behavioral targeting, RSS feed management, Social features, SPAM protection and Tag Management. 

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

**Personal identification information**

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, register on the site, place an order, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site and App. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number, date of birth, credit card information. Users may, however, visit our Site anonymously. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.

**Non-personal identification information**

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.

**How we use collected information**

Next Door Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:

  * _\- To improve customer service_  
Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
  * _\- To personalize user experience_  
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.
  * _\- To improve our Site_  
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.
  * _\- To process payments_  
We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.
  * _\- To send periodic emails_  
We may use the email address to send User information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.
  * _\- To send periodic sms_  
We may use your mobile number registered with us to send user information and updates pertaining to your transactions. It may also be used to respond to your queries, questions and/or other updates. By agreeing to these terms, you will receive sms that may include company news, alerts, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time you would like to opt out from receiving sms, you can write to us at support@onlinetyari.com. 

**How we protect your information**

We use HTTPS and encryption based network transmission to secure your data transfer. We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site and App. 

**OnlineTyari will never publicly disclose any personal or sensitive user data related to financial or payment activities or any government identification numbers. OnlineTyari don't allow unauthorized publishing or disclosure of people's non-public contacts.**

## Facebook permissions asked by OnlineTyari Platform

OnlineTyari Platform may ask for some Facebook permissions allowing it to perform actions with the User's Facebook account and to retrieve information, including Personal Data, from it. This service allows OnlineTyari Platform to connect with the User's account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook Inc.

For more information about the following permissions, refer to the [Facebook permissions documentation](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/authentication/permissions/) and to the [Facebook privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).

The permissions asked are the following:

### Basic information

By default, this includes certain User’s Data such as id, name, picture, gender, and their locale. Certain connections of the User, such as the Friends, are also available. If the User has made more of their Data public, more information will be available.

### About Me

Provides access to the 'About Me' section of the profile.

### Contact email

Access the User's contact email address.

### Photos

Provides access to the photos the User has uploaded, and photos the User has been tagged in.

## Device permissions for Personal Data access

Depending on the User's specific device, OnlineTyari Platform may request certain permissions that allow it to access the User's device Data as described below.

By default, these permissions must be granted by the User before the respective information can be accessed. Once the permission has been given, it can be revoked by the User at any time. In order to revoke these permissions, Users may refer to the device settings or contact the Owner for support at the contact details provided in the present document.  
The exact procedure for controlling app permissions may be dependent on the User's device and software.

Please note that the revoking of such permissions might impact the proper functioning of OnlineTyari Platform.

If User grants any of the permissions listed below, the respective Personal Data may be processed (i.e accessed to, modified or removed) by OnlineTyari Platform.

### Contacts permission

Used for accessing contacts and profiles on the User's device, including the changing of entries.

### Phone permission

Used for accessing a host of typical features associated with telephony. This enables, for instance, read-only access to the “phone state”, which means it enables access to the phone number of the device, current mobile network information, or the status of any ongoing calls.

### Precise location permission (non-continuous)

Used for accessing the User's precise device location. OnlineTyari Platform may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.  
The geographic location of the User is determined in a manner that isn't continuous. This means that it is impossible for OnlineTyari Platform to derive the exact position of the User on a continuous basis.

### SMS permission

Used for accessing features related to the User's messaging including the sending, receiving and reading of SMS.

### Storage permission

Used for accessing shared external storage, including the reading and adding of any items.

### Access to third-party accounts

This type of service allows OnlineTyari Platform to access Data from your account on a third-party service and perform actions with it.  
These services are not activated automatically, but require explicit authorization by the User.

#### Facebook account access (OnlineTyari Platform)

This service allows OnlineTyari Platform to connect with the User's account on the Facebook social network, provided by Facebook, Inc.

Permissions asked: About Me, Contact email and Photos. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php)

### Advertising

This type of service allows User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on OnlineTyari Platform, possibly based on User interests.  
This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside OnlineTyari Platform. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### Google AdSense (Google Inc.)

Google AdSense is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of OnlineTyari Platform and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.  
Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout).

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

#### AdMob (AdMob Google Inc.)

AdMob is an advertising service provided by AdMob Google Inc.  
**In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult[Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)**.

Personal Data collected: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

#### Facebook Audience Network (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Audience Network is an advertising service provided by Facebook, Inc. **In order to understand Facebook's use of Data, consult[Facebook's data policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).**

OnlineTyari Platform may use identifiers for mobile devices (including Android Advertising ID or Advertising Identifier for iOS, respectively) and technologies similar to cookies to run the Facebook Audience Network service. One of the ways Audience Network shows ads is by using the User's ad preferences. The User can control this in the [Facebook ad settings](https://www.facebook.com/ads/settings).

Users may opt-out of certain Audience Network targeting through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or by following the instructions in other Audience Network related sections of this privacy policy, if available.

Personal Data collected: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads)

#### DoubleClick for Publishers (Google Inc.)

DoubleClick for Publishers is an advertising service provided by Google Inc. that allows the Owner to run advertising campaigns in conjunction with external advertising networks that the Owner, unless otherwise specified in this document, has no direct relationship with. In order to opt out from being tracked by various advertising networks, Users may make use of [Youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). In order to understand Google's use of data, consult [Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).  
This service uses the “Doubleclick” Cookie, which tracks use of OnlineTyari Platform and User behavior concerning ads, products and services offered.  
Users may decide to disable all the Doubleclick Cookies by clicking on: [www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en).

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/)

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics for Firebase (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics for Firebase or Firebase Analytics is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. **In order to understand Google's use of Data, consult[Google's partner policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)**.

Firebase Analytics may share Data with other tools provided by Firebase, such as Crash Reporting, Authentication, Remote Config or Notifications. The User may check this privacy policy to find a detailed explanation about the other tools used by the Owner.

OnlineTyari Platform uses identifiers for mobile devices (including Android Advertising ID or Advertising Identifier for iOS, respectively) and technologies similar to cookies to run the Firebase Analytics service.

Users may opt-out of certain Firebase features through applicable device settings, such as the device advertising settings for mobile phones or by following the instructions in other Firebase related sections of this privacy policy, if available.

Personal Data collected: Cookies, unique device identifiers for advertising (Google Advertiser ID or IDFA, for example) and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

#### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of OnlineTyari Platform, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### Analytics collected directly (OnlineTyari Platform)

OnlineTyari Platform uses an internal analytics system that does not involve third parties.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

### Device permissions for Personal Data access

OnlineTyari Platform requests certain permissions from Users that allow it to access the User's device Data as described below.

#### Device permissions for Personal Data access (OnlineTyari Platform)

OnlineTyari Platform requests certain permissions from Users that allow it to access the User's device Data as summarized here and described within this document.

Personal Data collected: Contacts permission, Phone permission, Precise location permission (non-continuous), SMS permission and Storage permission. 

### Location-based interactions

#### Non-continuous geolocation (OnlineTyari Platform)

OnlineTyari Platform may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.  
Most browsers and devices provide tools to opt out from this feature by default. If explicit authorization has been provided, the User’s location data may be tracked by OnlineTyari Platform.  
The geographic location of the User is determined in a manner that isn't continuous, either at the specific request of the User or when the User doesn't point out its current location in the appropriate field and allows the application to detect the position automatically.

Personal Data collected: geographic position. 

### Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

#### Firebase Cloud Messaging (Google Inc.)

Firebase Cloud Messaging is a message sending service provided by Google, Inc. Firebase Cloud Messaging allows the Owner to send messages and notifications to Users across platforms such as Android, iOS, and the web. Messages can be sent to single devices, groups of devices, or specific topics or User segments.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

#### Firebase Notifications (Google Inc.)

Firebase Notifications is a message sending service provided by Google Inc. Firebase Notifications can be integrated with Firebase Analytics to target analytics-based audiences and track opening and conversion events.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

#### Amazon Simple Email Service (Amazon)

Amazon Simple Email Service is an email address management and message sending service provided by Amazon.com Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq/)

#### Sendgrid (Sendgrid)

Sendgrid is an email address management and message sending service provided by Sendgrid Inc.

Personal Data collected: email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://sendgrid.com/privacy)

### Managing support and contact requests

This type of service allows OnlineTyari Platform to manage support and contact requests received via email or by other means, such as the contact form.  
The Personal Data processed depend on the information provided by the User in the messages and the means used for communication (e.g. email address).

#### Zendesk (Zendesk)

Zendesk is a support and contact request management service provided by Zendesk Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/privacy)

#### Freshdesk (Freshdesk Inc.)

Freshdesk is a support and contact request management service provided by Freshdesk Inc.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://freshdesk.com/privacy)

### Registration and authentication

By registering or authenticating, Users allow OnlineTyari Platform to identify them and give them access to dedicated services.  
Depending on what is described below, third parties may provide registration and authentication services. In this case, OnlineTyari Platform will be able to access some Data, stored by these third-party services, for registration or identification purposes.

#### Direct registration (OnlineTyari Platform)

The User registers by filling out the registration form and providing the Personal Data directly to OnlineTyari Platform.

Personal Data collected: email address, first name, language, last name and phone number. 

#### Facebook Authentication (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Authentication is a registration and authentication service provided by Facebook, Inc. and is connected to the Facebook social network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260)

#### Google OAuth (Google Inc.)

Google OAuth is a registration and authentication service provided by Google Inc. and is connected to the Google network.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)

### Remarketing and behavioral targeting

This type of service allows OnlineTyari Platform and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of OnlineTyari Platform by the User.  
This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.  
In addition to any opt out offered by any of the services below, the User may opt out of a third-party service's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

#### AdWords Remarketing (Google Inc.)

AdWords Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the activity of OnlineTyari Platform with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

#### DoubleClick for Publishers Audience Extension (Google Inc.)

DoubleClick for Publishers Audience Extension is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that tracks the visitors of OnlineTyari Platform and allows selected advertising partners to display targeted ads across the web to them.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb#display_optout)

#### Facebook Custom Audience (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Custom Audience is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of OnlineTyari Platform with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

#### Facebook Remarketing (Facebook, Inc.)

Facebook Remarketing is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Facebook, Inc. that connects the activity of OnlineTyari Platform with the Facebook advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/)

#### Remarketing through Google Analytics for Display Advertising (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics for Display Advertising is a remarketing and behavioral targeting service provided by Google Inc. that connects the tracking activity performed by Google Analytics and its Cookies with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout)

### Tag Management

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on OnlineTyari Platform in a centralized fashion.  
This results in the Users' Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.

#### Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)

Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

## Further information about Personal Data

  * ### Push notifications

OnlineTyari Platform may send push notifications to the User.

  * ### Selling goods and services online

The Personal Data collected are used to provide the User with services or to sell goods, including payment and possible delivery.  
The Personal Data collected to complete the payment may include the credit card, the bank account used for the transfer, or any other means of payment envisaged. The kind of Data collected by OnlineTyari Platform depends on the payment system used.

  * ### The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13

Users declare themselves to be adult according to their applicable legislation. Minors may use OnlineTyari Platform only with the assistance of a parent or guardian. Under no circumstance persons under the age of 13 may use OnlineTyari Platform.

  * ### Unique device identification

OnlineTyari Platform may track Users by storing a unique identifier of their device, for analytics purposes or for storing Users' preferences.

  * ### User identification via a universally unique identifier (UUID)

OnlineTyari Platform may track Users by storing a so-called universally unique identifier (or short UUID) for analytics purposes or for storing Users' preferences. This identifier is generated upon installation of this Application, it persists between Application launches and updates, but it is lost when the User deletes the Application. A reinstall generates a new UUID.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:  
Next Door Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd 322, Okay Plus spaces  
Malviya Nagar   
Jaipur -302017   
Rajasthan  
support@onlinetyari.com
